proprivacy.com 2019-11-15

# Privacy - ProPrivacy.com

## Generally

ProPrivacy.com is part of a network of sites owned by 4Choice Ltd. At 4Choice we recognise the importance of your privacy. We are regulated by the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR). This policy will provide you with the following information:

  * why we are able to process your personal data
  * what purpose we are processing it for
  * whether you have to provide it to us
  * how long we store it for
  * whether there are other recipients of your personal information
  * whether we intend to transfer it to another country, and
  * whether we do automated decision-making or profiling.

This Privacy Policy may be required to be updated in the future to comply with any applicable European regulations, in order to utilise new technologies or to improve your experience, so please check back periodically.

## Who is our Data Protection Officer?

Our Data Protection Officer's is Simon Richardson. He can be contacted at compliance[at]vigoitsolutions.com

## How do we gather personal data?

Most of the personal information we process is provided to us directly by you for one of the following reasons:

  * You subscribe to our e-newsletter.
  * You have applied for a job with us.
  * You are representing your organisation.

## When you Contact Us

If you contact us via email, your details and a history of the communication will be stored by us in order for us to deal with enquiries adequately and improve our customer support services.

## When you access ProPrivacy.com

### Analytics

When you visit ProPrivacy.com, we use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to find out such things as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way that does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

If we do collect personal data through our website, we'll be upfront about this. We'll make it clear when we collect personal information and we'll explain what we intend to do with it.

### Cookies

We use a cookies tool on our website which relies on implied consent of users. In recognition of the fact that the implementation date for the revised e-Privacy Regulation remains unknown, we are taking reasonable steps now to align our use of cookies the standard of consent required by GDPR.

This means that we are in the process of implementing a tool which, by default, will require explicit opt in action by users of our website. This will apply to the non-necessary cookies. We will ensure any necessary cookies for functionality and security are marked so that they are not deleted by the tool.

### Purpose and legal basis for processing

The purpose for implementing all of the above is to maintain and monitor the performance of our website and to constantly look to improve the site and the services it offers to our users. The legal basis we rely on to process your personal data is article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR, which allows us to process personal data when its necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests.

## What are your rights?

As we are processing your personal data for our legitimate interests as stated above, you have the right to object to our processing of your personal data. There are legitimate reasons why we may refuse your objection, which depend on why we are processing it.

Under data protection law, you have rights we need to make you aware of. The rights available to you depend on our reason for processing your information.

### Your right of access

You have the right to ask us for copies of your personal information. This right always applies. There are some exemptions, which means you may not always receive all the information we process.

### Your right to rectification

You have the right to ask us to rectify information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to ask us to complete information you think is incomplete. This right always applies.

### Your right to erasure

You have the right to ask us to erase your personal information in certain circumstances.

### Your right to restriction of processing

You have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your information in certain circumstances.

### Your right to object to processing

You have the right to object to processing if we are able to process your information because it is in our legitimate interests.

### Your right to data portability

This only applies to information you have given us. You have the right to ask that we transfer the information you gave us from one organisation to another, or give it to you. The right only applies if we are processing information based on your consent.

You are not required to pay any charge for exercising your rights. We have one month to respond to you.

### Sharing your information

We will not share your information with any third parties for the purposes of direct marketing.

We use data processors who are third parties who provide elements of services for us. We have contracts in place with our data processors. This means that they cannot do anything with your personal information unless we have instructed them to do it. They will not share your personal information with any organisation apart from us. They will hold it securely and retain it for the period we instruct.

## Complaints

We work to high standards when it comes to processing your personal information. If you have queries or concerns, please contact our data protection officer.

## Children's information

We do not provide services directly to children or proactively collect their personal information. However, the information in the relevant parts of this notice applies to children as well as adults.

## Links and Affiliated sites

This site contains hypertext links to other sites, advertisers and other third parties. By clicking on any of these links, you are leaving the ProPrivacy.com website. ProPrivacy.com has no control over the information collected by any third party after you have left the www.ProPrivacy.com website. We advise and encourage you to read their privacy policies. 

The data collection and usage practices of any third party linked to ProPrivacy.com are not covered by this Privacy Policy. ProPrivacy.com assumes no liability and is not responsible for any practices of such third party websites, including their privacy practices or content. 

## Protecting your Information

We use a secure server cluster situated in a secure data centre to protect all the information you provide us with. We have invested heavily in equipment and highly qualified staff to ensure all information you enter is protected from access by any third party and only necessary and restricted access is available internally. We also protect all our connections to the Internet using various security measures including firewalls and regular security audits on all our servers. 

## Contacting ProPrivacy.com

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you may [contact us](https://proprivacy.com/contact-us).
